that's not the right camera
just I'm just posting up that was
shelling yo this is something you can do
this is something that you can do to
help right now there we go
you know fire blasts what's up hey
what's up yo welcome hi guys so what
we're here to show for today
it's called pencil there's been a lot of
people already hard at work so you can
go to our github URL right here uh
that's github calm / comment / Tomic
comma 10k and its 10k images for
training cigarettes yes it's comma
colouring 2.0 it's comma color 2.0 so
tesla has this thing called data engine
car path he loves to talk about it he
talks about it a lot of talks we of
course are too poor to afford a data
engine so we're relying on the kindness
of strangers and these strangers over
here this is our discord if you don't
know it's a discord comedy I have been
incredibly kind we're gonna go over to
comma pencil and they've already labeled
the first thousand images for us so we
can go through we can just take a look
at some of these here what's up Previn
they're really they're really beautiful
I think and it's easy because you don't
have to label things too many different
colors alright so um if I go here by the
way this is all open source so unlike
with comma pencil any work you do here
is available for anybody to use for any
purpose under the MIT license you see I
can go winning out here so one of the
beautiful things about comma segments is
we don't have many classes we don't have
many different kinds of stuff that you
have to label you don't need to know the
difference between someone who likes
watermelon and someone who doesn't like
watermelon or maybe those are three
different types of categories or you
know what's the difference between a
truck
and a pickup truck all right when is it
a truck when is it a car I don't know
but what I do know is that commas
categories are very simple five
categories see this purple here this
category is called my car anything that
is inside of your car and moves with you
some guy put a pizza box on the
windshield this is the my car category
this red here is a lane line we have
lane lines that dark brown is a road we
have everything else oh yes well the
green is movable so that's like cars and
pedestrians and horses anything else
that moves and then there's everything
else which is just that that grey there
all right
so yeah I mean you can see this is just
labeled from our users right here on our
github remember all this is open source
so we're going for ten thousand images
we're up to the number labeled so far
know what happened don't modify the
images folder oh we got a we fix the
test cuz I modified the images folder
but
that is how many we've labeled so far
ten that 1049 images so you can like
look at them they're really beautiful
you guys can look at me for a minute
I'm George my name is George when you
are on the internet sometimes and you
can find me on how many I just scored
well you can come help out right now
with the comet a eyepencil project while
I come fix this test we're going to fix
this test don't modify the image fall
that way what oh no
I need somebody else to fix this I don't
know how to fix that don't modify the
images follow thank you thank you I wish
we're just going in here we're gonna
we're gonna you guys want to see the
keyboard and I love seeing the qiblah
oh I'm just gonna go over got we gotta
fix this test because I don't want
people thinking that my test is broken
just puts just sad
oh this wasn't the right way to fix this
[Music]
just do it like that perfect see if this
one works so alright guys we fixed the
tests now we can get back to comma
penciling with you guys check out how
beautiful this image looks look at that
every little lane line right where it
belongs
and you guys can contribute to this huge
corpus of work that's publicly up on
github and is about to now have tests
that pass let's say if the tests pass
fix tests did I fix the tests oh I don't
know we're gonna find out so you ask
yourself how do I contribute to this and
Eric B has written this tool that you
guys can use called Image labeler
um image labels like the comma pencil
tool but it's better uh you can type in
like say I want to go to 50 or show the
existing mask this one's already really
well labeled but I can go to one that
like isn't labeled yet let's go to 1600
I'll show the existing mask for that oh
look at that look at that bug it's
really obvious you know especially if I
lower this down
no I don't you know it's not a bug no no
nevermind it's not obvious it's oh yeah
look okay you can see it you can see it
if the mass capacity is not that high
you see here this is actually not a part
of the truck it's a part of my car so I
can just go select my car here
go around this yeah yeah beautiful I
don't know if I see any other bugs with
this I think there might be some stuff
on labeled over here let's zoom in yeah
I think that's supposed to be a car
doesn't that look like a freight truck
to you I will just got a moveable label
this guy movable
drag those out a little bit well I want
to do that yeah yeah drag that there all
right cool all right
oh my there's like a little blah cheese
over there that aren't great but either
way this is a whole lot better than what
we had so when I'm ready I can just save
this mask it's downloaded here and then
you can commit that math on github I can
use the up and down arrows to change
opacity oh that's nice
awesome quality software oh yo Edwin
knows what's up um so yeah now I've made
this mask and now I you know if you're
gonna do it you should put a lot more
love and care and do it than I did we
really want these masks to be pixel
accurate and not have splotches like
that this is too low quality to commit
to our repo right over here in the comma
discord over in the comma pencil channel
and you guys can come help out so you
know Tesla has this they call it data
engine we don't have data engine because
we're poor guys we're poor comma doesn't
have a lot of money if you want to give
us money go to shop comment on the I and
by comma twos but I got the tool use pin
to all we should definitely do that oh
that's a good point yeah let me just so
I'm Eric B wrote this on discord it's a
great tool if he's doing a great job PGA
Laos done tons to you know actually
labeling images himself getting all this
stuff merging on github virtually Chris
has been helping out that got we've got
a great crew
shoutout to John Smith for buying a seat
- did you buy a commentator just buy
right now anyone who buys one right now
on this livestream I will shout you out
I will shout you out John Smith's cuz
play Oh guys guess what we sold today my
love would we sell these ok so I don't
know if you guys have been to comma a I
slash services but we sell some
ridiculously overpriced services to
people and we sold a meeting today we
sold a 30-minute phone call for $1000
John Smith bought one for one I don't
know my shout fight doesn't scroll back
that far that was so long ago um now you
know people aren't people aren't driving
as lunch with the UH you bought one
yesterday Michael horn no no I can I can
I can see you if you bought one
yesterday you did buy one yesterday Wow
oh yeah I'll ship tomorrow uh no I'm not
gonna show ya 30 minutes for $1,000
phone nope we're building something
incredible right now there's a quick
picture of it up on the discord but all
the comma twos that ship out from now on
are gonna have stress testing that's
super important but remember how can you
contribute oh I can't show you Shopify
um but I can show you comma 10k how can
you contribute go to this github URL
actually do I fix the tests well I fixed
that don't modify the images photos
that's good
the images are really honestly beautiful
so these are the ones that have already
been labeled now we can get to some of
them that haven't been labeled yet
yeah yeah so like these ones
well this one was automatically
generated so you can see that it's quite
good um so this this is an automatically
generated mask which means we just ran
it through the the comma automatic so if
you see that's quite good here it's
quite good here but it did miss this car
over here so you know we need somebody
to go in and just label that car maybe
that edge should be cleaned up a little
that's a little it's a little janky
looking yeah I don't know maybe that's
okay uh what do we have here again these
ones are all completely labeled by the
computer this one looks very good
already I don't know if there's any
problems with that one the only problem
I see is that if you zoom in here
there's a little bit of a little bit of
red there now remember that we don't
label crosswalks as Lane lines because
they're not lay mines they're crosswalks
now what do we got here oh this one's
pretty bad so you look at this unlabeled
Lane here remember every bug you see in
these images is a bug in open pilot so
every bug that you fix is a bug that
gets fixed and open pilot we're gonna
use this to regenerate all of our ground
truth once we have this segment um so if
you guys come a to our github come to
our discord remember that's discord
comedy I come in this channel right now
I'll post what you chatting on screen
right here yeah but people will help you
I know that we're gonna get play of this
later people will help you get set up
what is a segment a Sigma it's just
something that automatically labels that
so it's the machine that I use to
automatically generate this mask so
remember this one again and was
automatically generated by the machine
and that's why it's not perfect where
the human ones were much higher quality
cuz see it's not really a lame there
it's missing a little lane here that
stuff still all a road this one looks
pretty good it was like blotchy stuff
and that's a bug down there you see that
should be my car I should be part ball
again we're missing a center lane line
you know
ever had open pilot not detect your
center lane line well you can fix this
right now by contributing to common
pencil we're apparently missing an
entire semi every time you label a
picture the AI gets better exactly
exactly
you guys can contribute guys can label
data help me out this is the thing that
I've been using to test them off you
guys heard about big model look at big
model this is what the model currently
sees this is big model you know it's
like an ad for a widescreen camera we're
missing an entire salmon you guys want
to see we're missing an entire semi
what do you do if someone missed labels
we don't merge your pull request so this
is on github we have a system we are a
complex system place of checks and
balances we have an executive branch
allege no so like here this one ah see
and now we have virtually Chris came in
here on our public github here and it
was fine for you and it tries to put you
in another Lane well you guys you know
contribute see look look look look at
the detail here look at the detail
that's being called out all this is
incredible
see this is the kind of quality that's
gonna make open pilots so good I've been
super impressed with people's attention
to detail here uh yeah virtually Chris
has really been the guardian of the
guardian of quality so if you submit
something that's bad someone will call
you out on it and we'll get you to it
will get you to fix it up but yeah oh
yes you don't wish you were missing up
those people should be green and they're
not green those lane lines should be
colored an they're not colored an oh
this is pretty bad this one's pretty bad
we can do better here guys we can do
better you guys can do better we label
this one all this one's crispy
I just want to cite from like a few
mislabeled ley lines far off in the
distance that looks pretty perfect
this one's very good um big improvements
already one of the big improvements that
we didn't have before was all these
things used to not be labeled cars now
they're being labelled cars thanks to
thanks to people labeling them so that's
really nice
so few labels yeah we don't need a lot
of labels we're not Tesla is there no
way to use tinfoil contacts to improve
segmentation while moving so we actually
do that um we actually do the only
reason do we do some tutorials come into
common pencil and people will help you
get started um so we use temporal
context in the final ground-truthing
model like in the in the Ottoman so
these models are used as a component of
our automatic ground-truthing system for
the big models and the fact that they've
worked at all even with the super low
quality of data we've had is testament
to how good that temporal smoothing
works we don't want to put that temporal
smoothing in here because then you're
gonna get to poor correlation the beauty
of this is it's iid so we can you know
you can it's much easier to train models
when things are ID and you don't have to
deal with you know if you're gonna put
it into a filter later right like you if
you're gonna put some in a cow in felt
if you don't want to become poorly
correlated so that's why we do this like
this we don't try to exploit temporal
information here uh yeah let's look at a
few more let's call it a few more about
this one see this one is almost perfect
the only thing I would say here uh well
I wouldn't label those things Road
though they kind of are Road driveways
kind of our roads sometimes I don't know
I don't know if I'd call that a driveway
I don't know what people have been doing
coming to come with pencil and ask about
that um any thoughts about the
University of Toronto software and
Carcross I don't know anything about it
oh there's a bug there look that
shouldn't be powerful that's not part of
your car it's just a splotch on the road
leaned that up
that's that image by the way if you want
to come off yet hub right now fix that
one that one can be yours to fix for the
low price of zero dollars and cleanup
that maybe maybe add a little more I
think that Lane goes out a little bit
more I think you can kind of see it if
we zoom in a little bit there oh yeah oh
wow we're missing a vehicle off in the
distance oh that could be bad that could
be bad we want to definitely get that
vehicle labeled
yeah let's see that shouldn't be that
shouldn't be rode there
oh look at that one little lanes watch
never did a pretty good job with his
vehicles they remember these are the
ones they're being automatically
generated so if we look back at some of
the ones that were human labeled the
humans have really done a great job look
at this I don't know I bet we can't find
any bugs they've done a great job look
even got like a car over here and stuff
um so yet big props the humans because
really like how good this is saying in
machine learning
it's called garbage in garbage out but
you can take that saying and you can
also say quality in quality out maybe if
your machine learning is good you might
get garbage out but if you put quality
and that's where you got to start cars
and trucks green yeah the color standard
so the colors are all listed in the in
the readme here and we talked about what
the categories are here so oh yes you
guys are correcting the AI um the
categories are pretty simple so there is
no more we don't care about sky we don't
care about signs in traffic lights
anymore we just care about five
categories road lane markings
undriveable moveable and my car so Road
is all parts anyone nobody would look at
you funny for driving the driveway looks
real private know if a parking lot yes
don't include non lane markings
undriveable is anything you can't drive
on like the sky or like a concrete
barrier movable are like people and
vehicles and signs are also undriveable
right hand countries work fine yes
absolutely you know and on my desk
we've yawns and common tools was that
this new hardware um I have a neon
because oh no I did make a change today
notice how it doesn't say panda anymore
it says vehicle no GPS I'm not sure you
guys can really see it but this is
actually yellow because you're gonna
need to cuz this is a white panda this
is the greatest project you've heard
about so far thank you thank you so my
white panda and my comedy bug
no new hiver yeah so if you guys can
come onto our discord somebody will help
you out and yeah that's pretty much all
I have to say oh yeah if you want to
schedule a meeting
it's $1,000 we sold a meeting today I'm
so happy I love him we still meetings a
great victory so I might be meeting
tomorrow my $1,000 phone call
any idea why your Don your ego has your
default location wrong bro I don't know
I didn't write that code source check
that check source code check the check
the source all right cool any other
things for this dream well just look at
a bunch more pictures while we answer
any last questions beautiful these are
human label this is this is a testament
to what humans can do when they're
motivated look look at how far those
Lane goes oh yeah yeah beautiful is
there a channel yeah it's called kama
pencil in discord in the comedy hi
community discord yeah ah Oh beautiful
beautiful look at that look at that blue
reflection Oh still a vehicle 10,000
images to label yeah I mean so the thing
about 10,000 images it's already getting
a whole lot easier to label the images I
think by the time we're at the last
thousand we're gonna have to change
maybe a hundred of them and I think nine
hundred them are already gonna be
labeled completely correctly so we're
doing this iteratively I'll show you
yeah
let me find what I'm looking for this
one so you can see this is this is a
segment that I've been learning this
isn't a good example I've got a better
example up here I'm playing with
dynamics models here we got a second
extra day yeah yes you can see like
we're just we learn segments and then we
use it to predict and get these so as
you guys label images this ignites get
smarter the segment's get smarter we
have to label less and less things yeah
we trained entirely with
right-hand-drive stuff it'll be fine
we're gonna start paying you for column
points no nobody has bought the data yet
no nobody has bought the data we won't
pay you for comma points when reddit
pays you for karma that's that's what I
like to say about paying for common
points nobody's bought the data yet
unfortunately unfortunately guys and I
wouldn't sell the data to people if they
suck if they want to do ads you know
you no way mo sent us sauce and a
sent us I shouldn't say that I shouldn't
say that but you know Weibo I will
say that apparently apparently there's
this podcast and the podcast bleeped out
way mo and replace that with Taco Bell
because but just wait no socks no but um
I know any weird edge cases oh yes yes
and actually we'll show them to you
so hey virtually Chris welcome welcome
to the channel we'll show you the hard
ones
so we went out of our way to find a
hundred of the hardest images wow this
one's already been labeled by a human oh
this one's been labeled by a human as
well but wait till we get to some of
them that haven't been labeled by human
look at this guy
these are the hard ones wait'll we get
to the ones that haven't been labeled oh
yeah look at that look it's total trash
so we did a search yesterday for where
the models the most confused and then we
we put them we put them in oh yeah look
at this look at this trash it thinks
that's part of your car or that's junk
okay that one's good
someone probably do that goes oh look at
that aw it doesn't work at all those
police cars are clearly movable vehicles
can't even tell what they are
oh this is this is the worst one oh
what's the discord list discord comedy I
wow yeah this one's really bad you guys
can fix that one it's called H zero zero
nine and it's called H cuz the H stands
for hard Oh terrible oh that's terrible
oh this one's someone dead like this
pretty beautiful oh oh look
all that vehicles is coming right for us
bro is coming right for us someone
better label it real fast
look it fix those lights our lane lines
that's how atrocious this is Wow look at
that mislabelling terrible terrible
didn't do so bad at that one but yeah we
went through and I filtered out what the
hardest ones were yeah we got AK master
the Carl had us come on label label
label huh so yeah if you can come in and
help out on how to accept lane marking
tab enter I don't know what that means
um but look oh look at this look at this
terrible image look look at how bad it
is at this poor car he has clearly a car
plans for zero eight white pandas no
longer supported look at that vehicle no
GPS no we're gonna we're doing lots of
stuff with the localizer to start to
actually drive using the localizer to
put information back into the vehicle
basically we're approving the vehicle
model so it won't like drift out on
turns anymore we're looking at the
hugging issues and we're looking into
big model if we ship big model if we
ever ship big model it'll ship in the
zero eight I think zero eight is a
beautiful time for big model look at how
much more model we can see there's the
outline for zero rates on on the Oakland
pilot uh github is ball GMC yukon XL no
no don't buy that no fire open power
compatible car but I can't ice nada look
at that I've got to fix that move over
for Sammy yeah it's hung cruises I have
one song on Spotify parking lines or
lane lines no parking lines are not line
lines now only if they're used to mark a
lane I'll look at this also I think
someone labeled us why this one was
already just good you know I think
someone labeled us oh that's nice us
crispy crispy all right I'll leave you
guys with one of my favorite I think it
was 57 57 is one of my favorite yes
Ritchie's English enriches your English
Hyundai harness I don't know what to ask
the gender harness team yeah that was
labeled it makes a huge difference this
one looks kind wasn't really labeled
look is that stuff still wrong but this
one's already pretty good Ritchie's
English and riches are English so I'm
gonna leave you guys with thank you for
watching make sure to check out calm up
pencil on this cord everywhere label
images help us out
don't make us you know like Tesla had to
like pay a lot of money for this and you
know like let me tell you something
who cares more you when it's your open
pilot that's gonna miss the tech delay
nor miss detector car or some random guy
in the Philippines who can never afford
a Tesla in his life that's right you
this is a community-supported project i
really value you all thank you so much
for coming in to help out if you have
and if you haven't come in and help out
if you have no intention to come and get
to help out and you're just here to
enjoy the show that's all good to thank
you all for watching good night well a
lot of people want that Hyundai harness
alright alright alright I hear you I
hear you I hear you
yeah Ford sucks don't buy for